Friends, today I will tell you the complete process of downloading the
policy document of any vehicle just by the vehicle number.
For this, you will
not need to download any app.
You will be able to do everything from the mobile browser itself. So
let's start. For this,
you have to go to this Parivahan website. You will
come here and you will
see an option of Know Your Vehicle Details. Click on More Details.
Now to login, you will
create an account. Click on Create Account.
Then you will give your mobile number here and email
ID. Click on Generate OTP.
An OTP will be sent to this number and email.
Enter that OTP here and
click on Verify. Now here you will
write your full name and create a strong
password. Confirm the same password
again below.
Click on again. You will see a sample of the password here.
Then you have to create the password in the same way.
Then a message of Thank You will come.
Citizen user has been created successfully.
Click on Vehicle Search. Now
enter your mobile number here again,
then click on Next. Now
enter the same password here with which
you had just created.  Click on continue,
now you will give your vehicle number here,
enter this capture code, then
click on search there, then the
complete details of the RC will appear in front of you,
from where did you buy the vehicle, when was the vehicle registered,
who is the owner of the vehicle, along with this
you will also get the insurance details below,
from which insurance company you have insured your vehicle, it will be the
name of the company
and here you will also see its policy number,
so we have to download our policy
document here, for this
you have to copy or screenshot this policy number and
keep it with you, now to
download your insurance document,
open any browser, you will
come in the search bar, here you have to type
DigiLocker and
you have to open the first link that comes, now
click on sign here, if you
already have an account in Digi Locker, then here you will
give your Aadhar card number or mobile number, then you will give a 6-digit security pin,
click on sign, if your
account is created but you have forgotten the 6-digit
security pin, then for this
you have to click on Forgot Security PIN,
then enter your Aadhar card number or
mobile number  You will enter your number, then enter your date of birth
here, click on next,
you have to verify OTP, then
set a 6-digit security pin here and
if you are logging in to DigiLocker for the first time, then for this
you have to click on sign up below.
Creating a account in DigiLocker is
very easy, here you will
write your full name with the same spelling as your
name is written on your Aadhar card with this spelling, you will enter the
date of birth on the Aadhar card, you will enter the
date of birth here,
select your gender, give your mobile number,
set a 6-digit security pin,
give your email ID, give the Aadhar card number,
click on submit, then you have to
verify with OTP, then your
account will be created in DigiLocker here, as soon as you login, a
dashboard like this will appear,
click on the three lines here, then
click on search document, then
come to the search box and type
insurance here, as soon as you search, a
list of many insurance companies will appear in front of you,
you can select your insurance company from here if you want,
if you face any
problem in finding the insurance company here, for this you  What you have to do is
come back and then control down.
Here you will find different categories and
departments. Below here you will find
a section for banking and insurance.
Click on view all. Then a
list of all the insurance companies will appear in front of you
along with the logos of all the companies. From
here you have to
select the insurance company from which
you have insured your bike or car.
For example, if you have
taken insurance from Tata, then you will
see the data option here. You have to click on it.
Then you will get the policy document
option. Sometimes in other insurance
companies, you may
see different options for two wheeler and four wheeler.
So if you
want to download the insurance copy of a two wheeler, then you have to select two
wheeler.
If you want to download the insurance copy of a four wheeler, then
you will
click on four wheeler. In my case,
only the policy document is available here, so we
click on it. Now here you have to
enter the same policy number from which
you had just copied. Sometimes
on this page of other insurance companies,
apart from the policy number, you will be asked for options like this number or date.
Off-birth can also be requested. You need to enter whatever
details are asked from you here,
then click on Get Document. After
clicking on Get Document,
wait for a few seconds. Your
request has been submitted. You
may have to wait for a question here. A
message saying "Document Successfully" will appear, which
means that your document has been
successfully fetched in your DigiLocker. Now you need to
scroll down and a list of all the documents that
you have issued in DigiLocker will appear.
As you
can see, I have issued a lot of documents in my DigiLocker. If you
scroll down, you will also see a list of Tata's
insurance, that is, the one that I have just issued here.
Here
you will get the option to download it.
You can simply click on it, then
select PDF. The instance document of our vehicle has been
downloaded.
Let's open it. Here is your
vehicle's insurance copy. If you want, you
can also print it out directly from here by clicking on the three dots. Similarly,
Whenever you want to
download the original insurance copy of your vehicle, you
can download your insurance copy from here by logging into Busy Locker.